<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Cloud APIs]]></title>
  <link href="http://jyidiego.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jyidiego.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T04:48:10+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jyidiego.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[John Yi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Jclouds With Groovy: A Python Developers Point of View]]></title>
    <link href="http://jyidiego.github.io/blog/2014/02/17/exploring-jclouds-a-python-developers-point-of-view/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-17T15:49:25+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jyidiego.github.io/blog/2014/02/17/exploring-jclouds-a-python-developers-point-of-view</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most powerful features of Python is the REPL (Run, Evaluate, Print, and Loop) This allows developers
to run their code and get quick feedback. Developers are able test out new ideas and try
out different things without the cycle of modifiying, compiling, and running the source code.
One of the most useful things about Python&rsquo;s REPL is the introspection
capabilities. This allows developers to easily and dynamically explore libraries.
In the Java world there are a number of options to do this.
Java developers rely on their Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) to provide features
like object introspection, code completion, on the fly code analysis,
and quick access to help documentation. However most Python developers are not familiar with the
various Java IDEs and would need time to learn how to use their features.
They also may need to learn the Java language itself for a project. This is where Groovy makes a lot of sense.
Groovy is a dynamic language like Python and has
seamless integration to existing Java classes and libraires. Jclouds has become the defacto library
for multicloud infrastructures for Java developers. (The Python equivalent being libcloud
<a href="https://libcloud.readthedocs.org/en/latest/">https://libcloud.readthedocs.org/en/latest/</a>)
This blog will focus on exploring jclouds using Groovy.
To make the setup easy, I&rsquo;ll specify a very opinionated setup
running Ubuntu 12.04 with OpenJDK 7 patch 51. The code samples was created using a Ubuntu 12.04
image from Rackspace &ndash; [Ubuntu 12.04 LTS (Precise Pangolin) (PVHVM) (28b21a55-b686-4e8e-be9b-b6df2aaf60b8)]
however the precise64 virtualbox from Vagrant should as well. Finally
your environment should have access to the internet. So let&rsquo;s set this up:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>apt-get update
</span><span class='line'>apt-get -y install openjdk-7-jdk zip unzip maven2</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p></p>

<p>Groovy has a environment manager called gvm that is similiar in concept to the Ruby environment manager
rvm. I&rsquo;ve found this to be quite useful:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>export JAVA_HOME=/etc/alternatives/java
</span><span class='line'>curl -s get.gvmtool.net | bash</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>At this point gvm should be installed but you&rsquo;ll either have to source the gvm-init.sh or
restart the shell as specifed by the message upon gvm installation.
For most folks sourcing gvm-init.sh is easier.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>source "$HOME/.gvm/bin/gvm-init.sh"</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>You&rsquo;ll now want to install the latest version of Groovy. At the time of this post the latest version is 2.2.1,
however you can run the command below to install the latest version:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>gvm install groovy</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
